Rockefeller Family Public Relations Department papers, Series 1-9 FA789A
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Family Members and Interests, 1946-1961; 7; 4.18 Cubic Feet 11 letter document boxes
  - Laurance S. Rockefeller - Dorado Beach, 1954-1961 (Box 58, Folder 587)
    LSR purchase of property, opening program, gambling issue. Canada Golf. Literature.
  - Laurance S. Rockefeller - General, 1946-1954 (Box 58, Folder 588)
  - Laurance S. Rockefeller - Jackson Hole Preserve, Inc., 1953 (Box 58, Folder 589)
    New York office responsible for JHPI public relations. Plans for public relations program. Literature.
  - Laurance S. Rockefeller - Jackson Hole Preserve - Tourtellot Report, 1957 (Box 58, Folder 590)
  - Laurance S. Rockefeller - Jackson Hole and Grand Teton National Park, 1955-1957 (Box 59, Folder 591)
    Conditions in park. Opening and operation of Lodge.
  - Laurance S. Rockefeller - Memorial Center - James Ewing Hospital, 1952-1958 (Box 59, Folder 592)
    LSR contribution toward publication costs of book on cancer by Francelia Butler; relationship between Sloan Kettering Institute and Memorial.
  - Laurance S. Rockefeller - New York City Airport Authority, 1947 (Box 59, Folder 593)
    LSR chairman of authority. Plans for construction of Idlewild, LSR statements.
  - Laurance S. Rockefeller - Princeton University - Forrestal Research Center, 1953 (Box 59, Folder 594)
    Purchase and gift of Forrestal papers to Princeton by LSR and Dillon. Comments on press release.
  - Laurance S. Rockefeller - YWCA, 1953-1958 (Box 59, Folder 595)
    Public relations advise Mrs.. LSR on activities of YWCA.
  - David Rockefeller - Biographies, 1947-1961 (Box 59, Folder 596)
    Office prepared biographies.
  - David Rockefeller - Institute of International Education, 1954-1961 (Box 59, Folder 597)
    DR article on International House in News Bulletin of Institute, 1954; JDR 3rd declines to speak on international cultural relations; NAR declines service on Advisory Council for Conference on Exchanges of the Arts; JDR 3rd declines service in Conferences December 1956; Mr. and Mrs.. NAR agree to serve as patrons of dinner dance March 1960; JDR 3rd declines invitation to speak before Southwest Advisory Committee March 1961.
  - David Rockefeller - International House - New York City, 1949 (Box 59, Folder 598)
    Preparation of August 4, 1949 press release re. election of President Miguel Aleman Valdes of Mexico, Mrs.. Eleanor Roosevelt, and JDR, Jr. as first honorary members of International House Association, Inc. Announcement made by Dr. R. G. Sproul, Pres. of Board of Trustees.
  - David Rockefeller - The Story of International House, 1953-1961 (Box 59, Folder 599)
    by Harry Edmonds
  - David Rockefeller - International House- New York City - Gen. G. C. Marshall, 1947-1949 (Box 59, Folder 600)
    Marshall became Chairman of the Board, 1949; preparation of press release re. Marshall acceptance of post; DR introduction for Marshall and Gen. Frederick Osborn.
  - David Rockefeller - International House - New York City - Cafeteria Strike, 1948 (Box 59, Folder 601)
    Instituting mechanism to voice student grievances; statement by Board of Trustees re. financial situation and cafeteria problems; cafeteria strike.
  - David Rockefeller - International House - New York City - 25th Anniversary, 1950 May (Box 59, Folder 602)
    Preparation of press releases re. anniversary; Chinese Communist meeting February 1950; art exhibit April 1950; DR statement to be read at dance at International House April 29, 1950.
  - David Rockefeller - International House Association, Inc., 1947-1956 (Box 59, Folder 603)
    Creation of the association, 1947; changes in staff; preparation of press release; International House opening ceremonies 1955.
  - David Rockefeller - International House - Ford Foundation Presentation, 1952 (Box 60, Folder 604)
    General background of International Houses and International House Association, finances, management programs.
  - David Rockefeller - International House - Philadelphia, 1954 (Box 60, Folder 605)
    Trustees and staff; Walter C. Pew invitation to DR - recommendation.
  - David Rockefeller - Morningside Heights, 1947-1958 (Box 60, Folder 606-609)
    School survey, organization of REMDCO. Community re-development survey. Plans for housing re-development. Objections to plans. Selling the project to the people. Approval of project. Relations with General Grant public housing. Congressional fight over funding. Relocation problems. Building Morningside Gardens. Public safety.
  - David Rockefeller - Morningside Heights - Certificates, Resolutions, Minutes, 1947-1952 (Box 61, Folder 610)
  - David Rockefeller - Morningside Heights - Printed Material, 1947 (Box 61, Folder 611-613)
  - David Rockefeller - Morningside Heights - W.K. Harrison, 1947 (Box 61, Folder 614)
  - David Rockefeller - University of Chicago - Chicago Maroon, 1952 (Box 61, Folder 615)
    Charges of being communist made against University; Public Relations concludes that Maroon cannot fairly be termed a communist organ and that charges are greatly exaggerated.
  - Rockefeller Family - Publicity, 1947-1960 (Box 62, Folder 616-617)
    Clippings and articles.
  - Public Attitudes Toward the Rockefellers, 1970 (Box 62, Folder 618)
    Lloyd A. Free report on public opinions/attitudes regarding the Rockefeller family.
  - John D. Rockefeller 3rd - Memorial Service, Riverside Church, 1978 (Box 62, Folder 619)
    Copies of memorial booklet.
- Articles and Books Correspondence, 1914-1981; 1947-1962; 8; 8,8 Cubic Feet 15 containers. Extent is approximate.
  - The American Mercury - "Philanthropy Faces A Change" Winthrop Rockefeller, 1953 (Box 62, Folder 620)
  - American Weekly - Ray Josephs, 1947-1954 (Box 62, Folder 621)
    Public Relations comments on articles by Josephs concerning VBEC and NAR - "Hard Working Millionaire", American Weekly July 19, 1953; questions NAR's "time saving methods".
  - Americas - Proposed Article by Nelson A. Rockefeller, 1949 (Box 62, Folder 622)
  - Arne, Sigrid - Nelson A. Rockefeller Article, 1954 (Box 63, Folder 623)
  - Art in America - Article by Nelson A. Rockefeller, 1957-1958 (Box 63, Folder 624)
    American Indian Art, stone sculptures, Duck River County, Tennessee.
  - Asahi Magazine (Japan) - John D. Rockefeller 3rd Article, 1953 (Box 63, Folder 625)
    JDR 3rd as President of Japan Society.
  - Associated Press - David, Steven V., 1953 (Box 63, Folder 626)
    Copies of articles regarding the activities of the Rockefeller brothers.
  - Associated Press - Clarke, Philip C., 1947 (Box 63, Folder 627)
    Copy of interview with Nelson A. Rockefeller.
  - Associated Press - Tucker, George, 1949 (Box 63, Folder 628)
    Copy of articles about Nelson A. Rockefeller and IBEC.
  - Associated Press - Wiznitzer, Louis, 1957-1958 (Box 63, Folder 629)
    Copies of articles about Nelson A. Rockefeller, Brazil, economic development.
  - Atlantic Monthly - "American Technology for Starved Lands" Robert Price Russell, 1947 (Box 63, Folder 630)
  - Automoveis E Acessorios - "Reviewing Rockefeller", 1948 (Box 63, Folder 631)
    Copy of article regarding Nelson A. Rockefeller and IBEC.
  - Barr, Stringfellow - "Let's Join the Human Race", 1951 (Box 63, Folder 632)
    Letter to FAJ from W. Barclay Harding expressing his doubts about Barr's intellectual honesty; FAJ response that Barr had studied work of AIA although it was not mentioned in his report. JDR, Jr. letter to FAJ re. comments of Remsen Bird and H. C. McClellan.
  - Barbosa-Carneiro - IBEC Articles, 1947 (Box 63, Folder 633)
    Correspondence regarding representation of Nelson A. Rockefeller, IBEC, Brazil, Venezuela.
  - Bealle, Morris A. - "House of Rockefeller", 1959-1961 (Box 63, Folder 634)
  - Belgian Chamber of Commerce - "Albertville - Belgian Congo" Laurance S. Rockefeller, 1954 (Box 63, Folder 635)
  - Bingham, Jonathan B., 1953-1954 (Box 63, Folder 636)
    NAR's preface for Binham's book "Shirt-Sleeve Diplomacy", was not completed.
  - Boston Globe - Various Nelson A. Rockefeller Articles, 1946-1956 (Box 63, Folder 637)
    "Rockefeller Predicts Inter-American Trade Expansion" and other untitled articles.
  - Business Week - "10 Year Dream Turns A Profit" Sol Sanders, 1957 (Box 63, Folder 638)
    Nelson A. Rockefeller and IBEC
  - Business Week - "Good Neighbor, Good Business", 1947 (Box 63, Folder 639)
    IBEC article
  - Cargill News - "Brazilian Project Goes Forward" J.M. Wilson, 1948 (Box 63, Folder 640)
  - Caracas Journal 10th Anniversary Edition, 1955 (Box 63, Folder 641)
    Correspondence regarding IBEC Venezuela article.
  - Chilean Gazette - Nelson A. Rockefeller Statement, 1946 (Box 63, Folder 642)
  - Christian Science Monitor - "Rockefeller Sparks Business Leaders" Arnold Beichman, 1958 (Box 63, Folder 643)
  - Christian Science Monitor - "Rockefeller Pushes Program of "Joint Enterprise" for Latin America" Robert Shellaby, 1948 (Box 63, Folder 644)
  - Christian Science Monitor - "Pattern of Partnership Spurs Economic Development Abroad" Nelson A. Rockefeller, 1957 (Box 63, Folder 645)
  - Christian Science Monitor - Hallet Series, 1952-1954 (Box 63, Folder 646)
    AIA, IBEC-VBEC articles
  - Colliers - "How to be a Millionaire -- And Like It" C.D. Morris, 1950 (Box 63, Folder 647)
  - Colliers - "The Rockefellers of New York" Quentin Reynolds, 1949 (Box 63, Folder 648)
    Correspondence, unpublished article.
  - Coronet - "Rockefeller Center" Laurance S. Rockefeller, 1955 (Box 63, Folder 649)
  - Coronet - "The Rockefeller Story", 1950 (Box 63, Folder 650)
    Correspondence, reactions, and corrections.
  - Dartmouth Magazine - Article by Nelson A. Rockefeller, 1946 (Box 63, Folder 651)
    Copy of article regarding Latin America.
  - Diario Carioca - Statement by Nelson A. Rockefeller, 1952 (Box 63, Folder 652)
  - Ebony Magazine - "Rockefeller's Right Hand Man", 1955 (Box 63, Folder 653)
    United Negro Fund, The Future of Negro Colleges, Laurance Rockefeller and Winthrop Rockefeller statements.
  - The Economist - "Oil in the Third Generation" Mildred Adams, 1959 (Box 63, Folder 654)
    Copy of article and request for review.
  - Encyclopedia Britannica, 1955 (Box 64, Folder 655)
    Rockefellers re-write of the 1944 Edition
  - Engineering News Record - IBEC Technical Services (ITS), 1948-1949 (Box 64, Folder 656)
    Correspondence and copies of articles.
  - Esquire Magazine - Museum of Primitive Art (MOPA), 1957 (Box 64, Folder 657)
  - Export Trade and Shipper - "President, International Basic Economy Corporation" Robert C. Fulton, Jr., 1954 (Box 64, Folder 658)
  - A Fazenda - "New Methods for Control of Cattle Tick in Brazil" John B. Griffing, 1948 (Box 64, Folder 659)
    Copy of article.
  - Folha da Manha - Excerpts, 1949 (Box 64, Folder 660)
    IBEC operations at Sementes Agroceres' Santa Rita farm, Cargill, EMA operations at Jacarezinho, AIA work in Santa Rita do Passa Quatro.
  - Foreign Affairs Magazine - "Purpose and Policy" Nelson A. Rockefeller, 1960 (Box 64, Folder 661)
    Copy of article and magazine.
  - Foreign Affairs Magazine - Japan Article by John D. Rockefeller 3rd, 1954 (Box 64, Folder 662)
    Correspondence and suggested edits.
  - "Foreign Trade" - John D. Rockefeller 3rd, 1954-1955 (Box 64, Folder 663)
    Published in New York Times, article on Japanese trade.
  - Fortune Magazine, 1948-1957 (Box 64, Folder 664)
    Correspondence and corrections for various article about Nelson A. Rockefeller, IBEC, Venture Capital, the Rockefeller Brothers
  - Fosdick, Raymond - "A Portrait of John D. Rockefeller, Jr.", 1956-1959 (Box 64, Folder 665)
  - Free World Magazine - "The Only War We Seek" Nelson A. Rockefeller, 1951 (Box 64, Folder 666)
  - Goodfriend, Arthur, 1950-1957 (Box 64, Folder 667)
    Comments on content of his work "Dollars Won't Do It"; JDR 3rd contributed to cost of publication; criticism of "Report on Indohesia - background material on Goodfriend and comments on his other works; JDR 3rd Contribution to underwrite book Fifth Trip to Asia withdrawn when publishers turned the book down.
  - Grimm, Peter - "How I Bought the Site for Rockefeller Center", 1954 (Box 64, Folder 668)
  - Gronowicz, Antoni, 1958-1960 (Box 64, Folder 669)
    He interviewed JDR 3rd for book Builders of America; JDR 3rd was discouraged from contributing to book; Granowicz apparently abandoned proposed biography The Amazing Mr. John.
  - Griffing, John B., 1956-1960 (Box 64, Folder 670)
    Wrote articles concerning IBEC proposed projects for process ing of agricultural products in Brazil; aided in campaign for acceptance of processing soluble coffee in Brazil when Brazilian press opposed opening plants in the country; articles on corn, bamboo and new animal types, including cofee trees, fish farming. Griffing retirement.
  - Harrison, Wallace K., 1951-1961 (Box 65, Folder 671)
    Director of Planning for United Nations Headquarters; was named President of AIA. Harrison was also director of IBEC and IBEC Housing Corp. and Trustee of Rockefeller Foundation. Proposed profile of Harrison for The New Yorker; arrangements for proposed book of Harrison's work; copies of speeches made by Harrison.
  - HOY Magazine - Rockefeller Center, 1952 (Box 65, Folder 672)
    Interview with NAR.
  - Jewish Daily Forward - 300th Anniversary, 1954 (Box 65, Folder 673)
    DR statement on 300th Anniversary of landing of first jewish settlers in North America, July 18, 1954; DR was interviewed by S. Regensburg but no copy of the article was included
  - Jewish Labor Record, 1946 (Box 65, Folder 674)
    NAR Statement as Chairman of Community Committee on behalf of the United Jewish Appeal, June 1946.
  - Josephs, Raymond, 1947-1954 (Box 65, Folder 675)
  - Josephson, Emanuel M., 1952-1959 (Box 65, Folder 676)
    Author of "RockefellerInternationalist" and other attachs. on the family.
  - Journal of Commerce - Pan American Day Supplement, Nelson A. Rockefeller, 1953 (Box 65, Folder 677)
    Article by NAR (as Pres. of IBEC) for the Foreign Trade Issue September 1947; NAR articles for Pan American Day Supplements, 1947, 1948 and 1953.
  - Kissinger, Henry A., 1945-1957 (Box 65, Folder 678)
    Reprint of article from ForeignAffairs, "Reflections on American Diplomacy", 1956; Carnegie Corporation Quarterly July 1957 comment on Kissinger's Nuclear Weapons and Foreign Policy.
  - La Hacienda, 1949-1957 (Box 65, Folder 679)
    IBEC, Nelson A. Rockefeller
  - The Lamp, 1947-1948 (Box 65, Folder 680)
    VBEC articles.
  - Lares, Arturo - "El Diario de Nueva York", 1949-1959 (Box 65, Folder 681)
    Reprinted a series of very unfavorable articles about VBEC written by German Vegas for El Universal of Caracas. PR suggested El Diario publish the office's response to the attacks as was done by El Universal. El Diario sent a reporter to interview NAR instead. PR checked the draft of the article. Copies of editorials, NAR statements.
  - Life Magazine - Nelson A. Rockefeller Family, 1958-1960 (Box 65, Folder 682)
  - London Economist - "Rockefeller Deal for South America", 1948 (Box 65, Folder 683)
  - Magazines A-Z, 1954-1960 (Box 65, Folder 684)
    Business Week, Catholic Digest, "What has Changed in Kremlin?", David Rockefeller film for Family Circle magazine, Faith Today, True Confessions article re Winthrop's marriage, "Three Years of It" Harpers article, LOOK magazine article on NAR, New Leader magaine, Our World magazine, National Review re NAR, Reader's Digest re Lincoln Center, Sports Illustrated re JDR 3rd and tennis, This Week magazine, This World, Wisdom award NAR.
  - Mainichi - New Year's Message, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Japan, 1955 (Box 65, Folder 685)
  - Manchester, William - Holiday Articles, 1958 (Box 65, Folder 686)
  - Morris, Joe Alex, 1950-1956 (Box 66, Folder 687)
    Comments on report "U.S. International Security Objectives and Stragegy". Information on brother's houses and offer of use of apartment in NY for Morris and family.
  - Nation's Business - "Good Neighbors and Profits" J.W. White, 1949 (Box 66, Folder 688)
  - National Review - "When A Rockefeller Needs A Friend", 1958 (Box 66, Folder 689)
  - Nelson A. Rockefeller - Articles about, 1946-1948 (Box 66, Folder 690)
    Various articles about NAR and Latin America
  - Nelson A. Rockefeller - Articles by, 1947-1957 (Box 66, Folder 691)
  - New York Post, 1957-1959 (Box 66, Folder 692)
    Notes of NAR interview by Oliver Pilat corrected by Public Relations; interview with Mrs. LSR for article.
  - New York Times, 1947-1952 (Box 66, Folder 693)
    Articles about incorporation of IBEC. "Rockefellers Set Up Corporation to Improve Agriculture in Brazil, January 1947; June 1947 article "Venezuela to Get Food - Making Help". about fish and miik-powder plants planned by VBEC and Venezuelan government; editorial June 28, 1947 on Venezuelan experiment; January 4, 1952 article about Rockefeller interests in South America - IBEC and AIA; correspondence with Foster Hailey, incl. that about musician Linn Won-Sik and philologist Duncan MacDougal - NAR contributed toward Linn's expenses at Julliard; editorial re. AIA aid in Brazil January 23, 1952.
  - New York Sun, 1947 (Box 66, Folder 694)
    Editorial "More food for Venezuela", June 30, 1947.
  - New Yorker, 1942 (Box 66, Folder 695)
    Profile of NAR.
  - New Yorker - W.K. Harrison, 1954 (Box 66, Folder 696)
    U.S. Embassy building, Rio.
  - Newsweek Overseas Edition, 1948-1958 (Box 66, Folder 697)
    JDR 3rd.
  - New York Journal American, 1958 (Box 66, Folder 698)
    Clips of Watson's series "The Fabulous Rockefeller Dynasty", August 1958. Thank you note to Watson from JDR 3rd.
  - O Globo, 1946-1950 (Box 66, Folder 699)
    Article by FAJ December 26, 1946 re. cooperative programs between Brazilian and U.S. private groups :AIA and IBEC; NAR article on US-Brazil relations (PR recommendation that NAR back out if possible).
  - Owens, William A. - "Pocantico Hills 1609-1959", 1960 (Box 66, Folder 700)
    Copy of book and correspondence.
  - Read, Florence - "The Story of Spelman College", 1961 (Box 66, Folder 701)
  - Reader's Digest, 1955-1957 (Box 66, Folder 702)
  - New York Herald Tribune, 1958 (Box 66, Folder 703)
    R. Drummond guest column by NAR, about economic growth trend in the U.S. October 6, 1958.
  - Saturday Evening Post - "The Rockefeller" J.A. Morris, 1950-1951 (Box 67, Folder 704-706)
  - St. Louis Post-Dispatch, 1947 (Box 67, Folder 707)
    June 8, 1947 article on IBEC and NAR philosophy.
  - The Synagogue Light, 1946 (Box 67, Folder 708)
    Statement by NAR.
  - TIME - "Good Works at a Profit", 1948 (Box 67, Folder 709)
  - Town and Country - "Majesty in Manhattan", 1952 (Box 67, Folder 710)
    Copy of article re Rockefeller Center by Thomas Brailsford Felder.
  - Schwantes, Robert, 1955 (Box 67, Folder 711)
    "Japanese and Americans: A Century of Cultural Relations"
  - United Nations World, 1947 (Box 67, Folder 712)
    VBEC article, "Fresh Fish for Juan Bimba," "Rockefeller Name is Now Being Hailed by Venezuelans"
  - USIA, 1956 (Box 67, Folder 713)
    Statements by NAR
  - Vandenberg, Arthur, 1951 (Box 67, Folder 714)
    NAR and FAJ reactions to mentions of NAR in Vandenberg's publication of "PrivatePapers" All references to the UN San Francisco Conference.
  - Copies of Periodicals, A-Bui, 1922-1982 (Box 68, Folder 715-719)
    AAUW Journal, AIA Journal, Across the Board, Americas, Anglo-American Oil Company Limited Jubilee, The Architecture Forum, Architecture, Arkansas Water: Why Wait for the Crisis?, Art in America, Atlantik-Brucke E.V., Avenue, Belgian Congo-American Survey, Book Digest, Brazil, Brazilian Business, Brown Alumni Monthly, Buildings and Building Management.
  - Copies of Periodicals, Bus-I, 1914-1981 (Box 69, Folder 720-724)
    Business Week, Coronet, Energy in Solid Waste, Engineering News-Record, Esquire, Export Trade and Shipper, Family Circle, Family Weekly, Forests, Fortune, Finance, The FRA, Good Art is Good Business and Good Politics, How Rockefeller Built the Standard Oil Company, Institutional Investor, Investor's Reader.
  - Copies of Periodicals, L-S, 1938-1979 (Box 70, Folder 725-730)
    Life, Ladies' Home Journal, Look, The Ministry, Museum News, National Geographic, Naturalist - Jackson Hole Country, The Nelson Rockefeller Collection (Kykuit), The Nelson A. Rockefeller Collection of Mexican Folk Art (MOPA), New York, New York Times Magazine, Newsweek, Parade (Arkansas Gazette), Pageant, Parks and Recreation, People, People Places and Parties, Planning and Civic Comment, Population Council, Portrait of David Rockefeller (Kahn), Reader's Digest, Saturday Evening Post, Smithsonian, Sports Illustrated, Sunday Times Magazine.
  - Copies of Periodicals, T-Z, 1958-1981 (Box 71, Folder 731-733)
    Time, There are Many Washingtons,This Week (Detroit News), Town and Country, TV Guide, U.S. News and World Report, Yankee
  - Oversized Periodicals (Box 76, Box 77, Box 78, Box 79, Box 80)
    Life, Forutune, Holiday, and other oversize periodicals.
- Ivy Lee Correspondence and Clippings, 1915-1960; 9; 1.52 Cubic Feet 4 document boxes
  - Correspondence, 1919-1941 (Box 72, Folder 734-743)
  - Press Releases, 1925-1960 (Box 73, Folder 744-746)
  - Clippings, September 1946 - June 1947 (Box 73, Folder 747-748)
  - Clippings, July 1947 - June 1949 (Box 74, Folder 749-752)
  - Clippings, July 1949 - 1958 (Box 75, Folder 753-757)
  - Rockefeller Institute, 1915-1920 (Box 75, Folder 758)